cookingwithcurls.com 2019-12-05

# Privacy Policy - Cooking With Curls

## **Privacy Policy**

Cooking with Curls found at https://cookingwithcurls.com (“Website”) is governed by the following privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”).

We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting it. The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you what personally identifiable information we may collect and how it may be used. This statement only applies to this Website.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please see: [http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp)

### WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT AND HOW IS IT USED?

**Information You Voluntarily Submit to the Website**

We may collect personal information from you such as your name or email address. For example, you may voluntarily submit information to the Website by leaving a comment, subscribing to a newsletter, or submitting a contact form. In addition, you are able to create a user profile, which allows you to create a username and password. We will store the username, but your password will not be visible in our records.

**Information We Collect from Others**

We may receive information about you from other sources. You may link your Facebook, Instagram, and/or Google accounts to your user profile. If you choose to link your Facebook, Instagram, and/or Google accounts to your user profile, we will receive your name, email address and profile picture associated with that account.

**Automatically-Collected Information**

Like many other Web sites, cookingwithcurls.com makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider (ISP), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable.

**Cookies**

A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. Cookies may be either “persistent” cookies or “session” cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed. Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

Users may, at any time, prevent the setting of cookies, by the Website, by using a corresponding setting of your internet browser and may thus permanently deny the setting of cookies. Furthermore, already set cookies may be deleted at any time via an Internet browser or other software programs. This is possible in all popular Internet browsers. However, if users deactivate the setting of cookies in your Internet browser, not all functions of our Website may be entirely usable.

You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/). You can also opt out of the network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative’s multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: [http://optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/). However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained.

### HOW YOUR INFORMATION MAY BE USED

We may use the information collected in the following ways:

To operate and maintain the Website;  
To create your account, identify you as a user of the Website, and customize the Website for your account;  
To send you promotional information, such as newsletters. Each email promotion will provide information on how to opt-out of future mailings;  
To send you administrative communications, such as administrative emails, confirmation emails, technical notices, updates on policies, or security alerts;  
To respond to your comments or inquiries;  
To provide you with user support;  
To track and measure advertising on the Website;  
To protect, investigate, and deter against unauthorized or illegal activity.

### **Doubleclick Dart Cookie**

Google, as a third party advertisement vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on cookingwithcurls.com. The use of DART cookies by Google enables them to serve adverts to visitors that are based on their visits to this website as well as other sites on the internet.

To opt out of the DART cookies you may visit the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following url: <http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html> Tracking of users through the DART cookie mechanisms are subject to Google’s own privacy policies.

Other Third Party ad servers or ad networks may also use cookies to track users activities on this Site to measure advertisement effectiveness and other reasons that will be provided in their own privacy policies. Cooking with Curls has no access or control over these cookies that may be used by third party advertisers.

**THIRD-PARTY USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

We may share your information with third parties when you explicitly authorize us to share your information.

Additionally, the Website may use third-party service providers to service various aspects of the Website. Each third-party service provider’s use of your personal information is dictated by their respective privacy policies.

### This Website Currently Uses the Following Third-Party Service Providers and Social Media Sites

**GoDaddy Hosting**

Purpose: The company and servers that host the database of our website

Personal Data: May collect and share encrypted personal information on our site visitors only to comply with legal processes (e.g. court orders, subpoena, law enforcement, regulation authorities).

Stored indefinitely to our knowledge.

<https://www.godaddy.com/agreements/showdoc.aspx?pageid=PRIVACY>

**WordPress (Automattic)**

Purpose: Content Management System that helps us build the front-end of our website.

Personal Data: WordPress uses Cookies. You may opt to share personal data such as your name, email address and personal communications when you leave a comment on Cooking with Curls.

This data is stored indefinitely.

<https://automattic.com/privacy/>

**Google Analytics**

Purpose: This service tracks Website usage and provides information such as referring websites and user actions on the Website.

Personal Data: Uses cookies with consent to collect general data. No personal data is collected. Your IP address is anonymized prior to collection.

All data is purged by Google Analytics every 14 months.

<https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites>

**Mail Chimp**

Purpose: This service is used for delivery of email updates and newsletters. We store your name and email address for purposes of delivering such communications.

Personal Data: Your email address, IP address, geolocation, name if supplied, an avatar if you’re a Gravatar user, general location. “Pixels” or “Web Beacons” are used to track email performance and collate email campaign reports.

Data is stored in the US by Mailchimp indefinitely. Please refer to Mail Chimp’s privacy policy for further information.

<https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/>

**Pinterest “Pin It” Button   **

Purpose: Lets visitors pin our content to Pinterest with ease

Data: Uses cookies to allow you to login to your Pinterest account and “Pin” an image.

Data is stored by Pinterest indefinitely.

<https://policy.pinterest.com/en/privacy-policy>

<https://policy.pinterest.com/en/cookies>

**Facebook**

Purpose: Facebook collects different information depending on how you use their products.

Data: Authentication, Security, site and product integrity, Advertising, recommendations, insights and measurement, Site features and services, Performance, Analytics and research

Facebook stores data until it is no longer necessary to provide our services and Facebook Products, or until your account is deleted – whichever comes first.

Please see Facebook’s Privacy Policy for more detailed information.

<https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/update>

**WP Recipe Maker  **

Bootstrapped Ventures, the developer of WP Recipe Maker, does not have access to any of the data collected by the plugin. This is all stored in your local database and not communicated back to us. Take note of the following topics for your own privacy policy.

**What personal data we collect and why we collect it**

Comments: When comment ratings are enabled we store the rating a user has given to a recipe along with the personal data WordPress core stores.

Cookies: When user ratings are enabled we store a WPRM_User_Voted_%recipe% cookie (with %recipe% the ID of the recipe) that contains the rating this user has given to a particular recipe. This cookie is used as (one of the) measures to prevent rating spam.

IP Address: When user ratings are enabled we store the IP address upon voting. This is used as (one of the) measures to prevent rating spam.

Their own manually input information

With the Recipe Submission feature personal data can be collected, depending on the fields that were added to the form. This can include the user email and name. When using the reCAPTCHA feature you will be agreeing to their terms of use and privacy policy.

### How long we retain your data

Our cookies are stored for 30 days. User submitted data is stored indefinitely in the local database.

At this time, your personal information is not shared with any other third-party applications. This list may be amended from time to time in the Website’s sole discretion.

Except when required by law, we will not sell, distribute, or reveal your email addresses or other personal information without your consent; however, we may disclose or transfer personal information collected through the Website to third parties who acquire all or a portion of our business, which may be the result of a merger, consolidation, or purchase of all or a portion of our assets, or in connection with any bankruptcy or reorganization proceeding brought by or against us.

**ANONYMOUS DATA**

From time to time, we may use anonymous data, which does not identify you alone, or when combined with data from other parties. This type of anonymous data may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses. Examples of this anonymous data may include analytics or information collected from cookies.

**PUBLICLY VISIBLE INFORMATION**

If you create a user profile on the Website or leave a comment, certain information may be publicly visible. To create a user profile, you must choose a username and password and input your email address for profile confirmation. Your email address will never be available publicly. At your option, you may also add an avatar, a profile description, and a link to your website.

You may also choose to link your Facebook, Instagram, and Google Account.

Users may see your username, avatar, profile description and website information.

**CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS**

California Civil Code Section 1798.83, also known as the “Shine The Light” law, permits our users who are California residents to request and obtain from us, once a year and free of charge, information about categories of personal information (if any) we disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes and the names and addresses of all third parties with which we shared personal information in the immediately preceding calendar year. If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please submit your request in writing to us using the contact information provided below.

If you are under 18 years of age, reside in California, and have provided your personal information with the Site, you have the right to request removal of unwanted data that you publicly post on the Site. To request removal of such data, please contact us using the contact information provided below, and include sufficient detail about the public post(s) and a statement that you reside in California. We will make sure the data is not publicly displayed on the Site, but please be aware that the data may not be completely or comprehensively removed from our systems, nor can we guarantee any cached or archived version of the site will remove such data.

## ADVERTISING

**Display Ads**

The Website uses Mediavine to manage all third-party advertising on the Website. Mediavine serves content and advertisements when you visit the Website, which may use cookies. Mediavine may collect IP addresses and location to serve personalized ads. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices to opt-in or opt-out of this data collection, please visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>.

**Retargeting Ads**

From time to time, the Website may engage in remarketing efforts with third-party companies, such as Google, Facebook, or Instagram, in order to market the Website. These companies use cookies to serve ads based on someone’s past visits to the Website.

**Affiliate Program Participation**

The Website may engage in affiliate marketing, which is done by embedding tracking links into the Website. If you click on a link for an affiliate partnership, a cookie will be placed on your browser to track any sales for purposes of commissions.

Cooking with Curls, Lisa Johnson, is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and links to Amazon.com. As part of this Amazon Associates program, the Website will post customized links, provided by Amazon, to track the referrals to their website. This program utilizes cookies to track visits for the purposes of assigning commission on these sales.

Please refer to Amazon’s Privacy Policy for more information.

[https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html/ref=footer_privacy?ie=UTF8&nodeId=468496](https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html/ref=footer_privacy?ie=UTF8&nodeId=468496&tag=cookwithcurl-20)

Products are featured on this blog’s Shop My Kitchen page and in blog posts.

This blog accepts forms of cash advertising, sponsorship, paid insertions or other forms of compensation. The compensation received will never influence the content, topics or posts made in this blog. All advertising is in the form of advertisements generated by a third party ad network.

Those advertisements will be identified as paid advertisements. The owner(s) of this blog is compensated to provide opinion on products, services, websites and various other topics. Even though the owner(s) of this blog receives compensation for our posts or advertisements, we always give our honest opinions, findings, beliefs, or experiences on those topics or products.

The views and opinions expressed on this blog are purely the bloggers own. Any product claim, statistic, quote or other representation about a product or service should be verified with the manufacturer, provider or party in question. This blog does not contain any content which might present a conflict of interest.

**Newsletters**

On the Website, you may subscribe to our newsletter, which may be used for advertising purposes. All newsletters sent may contain tracking pixels. The pixel is embedded in emails and allows an analysis of the success of online marketing campaigns. Because of these tracking pixels, we may see if and when you open an email and which links within the email you click. Also, this allows the Website to adapt the content of future newsletters to the interests of the user. This behavior will not be passed on to third parties.

### RIGHTS RELATED TO YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

**Opt-out**  – You may opt-out of future email communications by following the unsubscribe links in our emails. You may also notify us at lisa@cookingwithcurls.com to be removed from our mailing list.

**Access**  – You may access the personal information we have about you by submitting a request to lisa@cookingwithcurls.com

**Amend**  – You may contact us at lisa@cookingwithcurls.com to amend or update your personal information.

**Forget**  – In certain situations, you may request that we erase or forget your personal data. To do so, please submit a request to lisa@cookingwithcurls.com

Please note that we may need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes or to complete transactions, or when required by law.

**SENSITIVE PERSONAL INFORMATION**

At no time should you submit sensitive personal information to the Website. This includes your social security number, information regarding race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious beliefs, health information, criminal background, or trade union memberships. If you elect to submit such information to us, it will be subject to this Privacy Policy.

**CHILDREN’S INFORMATION**

The Website does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 16. If a parent or guardian believes that the Website has personally identifiable information of a child under the age of 16 in its database, please contact us immediately at lisa@cookingwithcurls.com and we will use our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.

**Security**

The security of your Personal Information is important to us, but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. We never sell your personal information to third parties.

### **Changes To This Privacy Policy**

We reserve the right to update or change our Privacy Policy at any time. You should check this page periodically to ensure that you are aware of the current policy. Your continued use of the Service after we post any modifications to the Privacy Policy on this page will constitute your acknowledgment of the modifications and your consent to abide and be bound by the modified Privacy Policy.

If you have any questions regarding the privacy policy of Cooking with Curls then you may contact us at lisa@cookingwithcurls.com.

Last updated: October 14, 2019.

### Nutrition Information Disclaimer

The writers and publishers of cookingwithcurls.com are not nutritionists or registered dietitians.

This website and recipes on cookingwithcurls.com, are produced for informational purposes only. Statements within this site have not been evaluated or approved by the Food and Drug Administration. This website is not intended to cure, prevent, diagnose or treat any disease. Content should not be considered a substitute for professional medical advice, expertise or treatment.

The reader assumes full responsibility for consulting a qualified health professional regarding health conditions or concerns, and before starting a new health program or diet. The writer(s) and publisher(s) of this site are not responsible for adverse reactions, effects, or consequences resulting from the use of any suggestions ore recipes herein or procedures undertaken hereafter.

This website is not intended as nutritional advice and readers of this website are ultimately responsible for all decisions pertaining to their health.

Occasionally, this website, cookingwithcurls.com, may offer estimated nutritional information for recipes contained on this website, such as calories, fat, carbs, etc. This information is provided as a courtesy and is not guaranteed to be accurate. This nutritional information comes from online calculators. Although cookingwithcurls.com attempts to provide accurate nutritional information, these figures are only estimates.

Various factors can change the nutritional information in any given recipe. These factors include but are not limited to the actual brands used. Also, different online calculators sometimes provide different results based on their own algorithms and nutrition fact sources. Under no circumstances will cookingwithcurls.com and the recipe creators be responsible for any loss or damage resulting from your reliance on the nutritional information that may be provided.

To obtain the most accurate representation of the nutritional information in any given recipe, you should calculate the nutritional information with the actual ingredients you use in your recipe, using your preferred nutrition calculator, or your own nutritionist or medical professional.  **You are solely responsible for ensuring that any nutritional information obtained is accurate.**

The writer(s) and publisher(s) of cookingwithcurls.com are not responsible for adverse reactions, consequences or effects, resulting from the use of any recipes or suggestions herein or procedures undertaken hereafter. This website is not intended as nutritional advice and readers of this website are ultimately responsible for all decisions pertaining to their health.

This website is not intended as nutritional advice and readers of this website are ultimately responsible for all decisions pertaining to their health.

### **Disclosure Statement**

This blog is a personal blog written and edited by me, Lisa Johnson. For questions about this blog, please contact  lisa@cookingwithcurls.com.

To get your own policy, go to http://www.disclosurepolicy.org
